<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Yang Sun</title><link href="http://yangsun.me/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://yangsun.me/feeds/all.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://yangsun.me/</id><updated>2016-02-22T19:56:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>First Garden Project - Grow My Own Strawberries</title><link href="http://yangsun.me/posts/2016-02/first-garden-project-grow-my-own-strawberries.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2016-02-22T19:56:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Yang Sun</name></author><id>tag:yangsun.me,2016-02-22:posts/2016-02/first-garden-project-grow-my-own-strawberries.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I came across the idea of growing strawberries at home few month back in the summer while I was shopping the supermarket. Every time I looked at the beautiful and delicious strawberries, I couldn't stop myself of pick up few boxes of strawberries. After I went back home, I immediately consumed two boxes of strawberries and decided to leave the other few boxes for tomorrow. The day after, when I picked up the strawberries from my fridge, the strawberries are starting rotted. Then, the idea of growing my own strawberries came into my mind. I did some quick search on the Internet and found out strawberry is easy to grow and low maintain plants, but the best time to plant strawberry is early spring and late winter, I already missed that period.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Few months later, I still keep the 'dream' of growing my own strawberry, and the time is just perfect - February. I googled on 'strawberry plant Ireland', about 238,000 results showed up. The first result from &lt;a href="www.englishsfruitnursery.ie/strawberries_plants_for_sale/"&gt;English's Fruit Nursery&lt;/a&gt; offers a variety of fruit plant, but they don't offer online order, so clicked on second result &lt;a href="strawberryplants.ie"&gt;Strawberry Plants Ireland&lt;/a&gt;. This website is dedicated to strawberry plants. They only offer four varieties of strawberry plants for sale with options of  potted and bare root plants.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The variety I ordered through &lt;a href="strawberryplants.ie/"&gt;Strawberry Plants Ireland&lt;/a&gt; is &lt;a href="http://strawberryplants.ie/bare-root-plants/elsanta-bare-root-strawberry-plant"&gt;Elsanta Bare Root Strawberry Plant&lt;/a&gt;. According to &lt;a href="strawberry plants.ie/"&gt;Strawberry Plants Ireland&lt;/a&gt;, Elsanta is:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The most popular variety in Northern Europe. Superb fruit quality and adaptability to many different growing systems make it our first choice.
Bare root strawberry plants are only suitable for planting from January to early April.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is just what I want - first choice! February is just perfect for bare root strawberry plants. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After ordered my 50 strawberry plants, I made a shopping list based on the advice from &lt;a href="https://www.quickcrop.ie/learning/plant/strawberry"&gt;Quickcrop&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://www.thegardenshop.ie/how-to-grow-strawberries/"&gt;The Garden Shop&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is my shopping list(price quote is for one item):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;50 x &lt;a href="http://strawberryplants.ie/bare-root-plants/elsanta-bare-root-strawberry-plant"&gt;Elsanta Bare Root Strawberry Plant&lt;/a&gt; (€1)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;12 x Strawberry Planter Trio Pot from Dealz (€1.49)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;10 x pot from Dealz (€1.49)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;3 x bag of organic compost(40L) from Aldi (€2.69)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 x Chicken manure pallet(7kg) from Aldi (#7.99)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2 x Time-release fertilizer from Dealz (€1.49)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 x Walk in greenhouse from Home Store (€24.99)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2 x Tomato liquid fertilizer from Dealz (€1.49)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That is €123.83 in total.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;How I plant my strawberry plants?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I ordered my strawberry plants from &lt;a href="strawberryplants.ie/"&gt;Strawberry Plants Ireland&lt;/a&gt; on Wednesday and they send out on the following Monday. The delivery took two days, so I got my strawberry plants on Wednesday. This is just a week after I made my order.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;After taking plants out of the boxes, I sprayed some water on the roots. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mixed one bottle of Time-release fertilizer with 120L of compost&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fill the pots with 2/3 full of compost&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Water the soil until the water starts to drain from the bottom of the pot&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Set a plant on top of each soil mound&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fill up the pots with compost&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Water the soil again&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The whole process took me about 2 hours as a novice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is own few days after the potting, so I can not tell how many strawberry plants are alive, but I will update after a month&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="garden"></category></entry><entry><title>Java SE 7 Programmer I Exam - Passed!</title><link href="http://yangsun.me/posts/2016-02/java-se-7-programmer-i-exam-passed.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2016-02-06T22:58:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Yang Sun</name></author><id>tag:yangsun.me,2016-02-06:posts/2016-02/java-se-7-programmer-i-exam-passed.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;After 5 days of reviewing my OCA Java SE 7 Programmer I Study Guide notes, I took the exam.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is my first attempt at official 1Z0-803 Java SE 7 Programmer I exam (aka OCA Java) after two mock exams with an average score of 68%. Guess what? I got 86%! Yes! I am now an Oracle certified Java programmer!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;The Exam Centre&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I took the exam in &lt;a href="http://www.theexamcentre.com/"&gt;The Exam Centre&lt;/a&gt;. It is located in the Leopardstown village, just of Leopardstown Luas stop. The exam centre is super easy to find and with plenty of parking spaces. I arrived 20 minutes earlier, the register process is quick and easy. Just a few minutes after, I completed few forms and have my photo taken at the reception. The friendly lady guide me to the room where the exam is taken place. The room has around 20 computers in their own cubics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;The Exam&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unlike the mock up exams included in the Java Study Guide, the official exam has 70 questions which include some question without mark. It takes me one hour and forty minutes to completed all the questions, which gave me few minutes to go back to the questions that I am not sure about.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Getting the Result&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just 15 minutes after the submitting my exam, the exam result email arrived in my inbox. I didn't feel any kind of nervous, as I know I definitely passed my exam. The 86% accuracy surprised me as I only got 68% in the mockup exam just the night before. I believe that the real exam is less tricky than the mock up exam which might be the main reason I get a better result.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;What's next?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The 1Z0-803 exam only gives me an Associate level certificate, in order to achieve a Professional level certificate, there is one more exam - 1Z0-804 which is the Part II of the Oracle Study Guide. The part I is merely over 300 pages which took me about two weeks full-time if i added up all the time I spent, but the part II is span over 600 pages - it's more than the double of the first part and even harder. I think 3 - 4 weeks might be a good estimate. Forgot to mention the good part of the 1Z0-804 exam, &lt;del&gt;it only cost about 100 euro&lt;/del&gt;(OK, I am wrong, it is the same price as part one exam - 212 euro)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As my week long holiday will finish next Monday, I will need to study after work which might even take more time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am going to use the same way to study the part two Study Guide&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Read the Study Guide&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Do the self-test after each chapter&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Read the book again and take notes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Do the self-test&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Try mock up exam&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Read the notes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Try mock up exam&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will have post my Part two notes Google Doc link HERE. &lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="java"></category><category term="certificate"></category><category term="exam"></category></entry><entry><title>My Domain Name is Back! - YangSun.me</title><link href="http://yangsun.me/posts/2016-02/my-domain-name-is-back-yangsun-me.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2016-02-04T12:45:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Yang Sun</name></author><id>tag:yangsun.me,2016-02-04:posts/2016-02/my-domain-name-is-back-yangsun-me.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I bought tons of domain in the last few years - qero.net, ebe.me, yang.so and the one I finally started using since yesterday afternoon - YangSun.me&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This domain was registered on an impulse in late 2014, but due to the workload from the study of my master course in UCD, it took me more than a year to get my hand on this domain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yesterday afternoon, I was reading a Java Cert book and started feeling boring with the tricky exam questions, so I did a quick lookup on my favourite domain reseller - &lt;a href="https://www.namecheap.com/?aff=96185"&gt;NameCheap&lt;/a&gt;. Yes! My expired domain can be registered now. I registered the domain and added three DNS settings, less than 12 hours, YangSun.me is up and running.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first time I notice &lt;a href="https://www.namecheap.com/?aff=96185"&gt;NameCheap&lt;/a&gt; is from GitHub. GitHub has a special perk for students called &lt;a href="https://education.github.com/pack"&gt;Student Developer Pack&lt;/a&gt;. The pack has many free bits for students(like free one year .me domain name from &lt;a href="https://www.namecheap.com/?aff=96185"&gt;NameCheap&lt;/a&gt;, free 50$ credit in &lt;a href="https://m.do.co/c/f68d634be5d8"&gt;DigitalOcean&lt;/a&gt;, and many more!)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This domain was first registered in December 2014 when I was attending my Master course in &lt;a href="http://www.ucd.ie"&gt;UCD&lt;/a&gt;. The main reason at that time was I want to create a website with my CV and my project on it. After I registered the domain for free with &lt;a href="https://www.namecheap.com/?aff=96185"&gt;NameCheap&lt;/a&gt;, I created an HTML page and link it to &lt;a href="http://github.com/s27y"&gt;my GitHub&lt;/a&gt;. Then I totally forgot about the website for a whole year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;What am I going do with this domain?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I always want to start writing to record the happiness, sadness and the random things happened in my life, but all I did was build a VPS/blog/WordPress and now pelican and then - totally forget about it after the website is up. This time, instead of building the website first, I am going to start writing first, then gradually improve the website.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;What about other domain names?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;ebe.me&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This domain was first registered five years ago when I was attending my undergraduate course in &lt;a href="www.dkit.ie"&gt;DKIT&lt;/a&gt;. Along with this domain, I also brought three years shared hosting plan from &lt;a href="www.goDadday.com"&gt;GoDaddy&lt;/a&gt;. At 2011, there was not much choice I can use to build a blog on a shared hosting plan, so I set up a WordPress on it, and I did wrote few blogs there in Chinese. Not long, it was abandoned.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;yang.so&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is my first attempt to create a personal brand - So Yang(So Young). I tried to write some Linux tips and hints on it, but then i gave up.
I am gooing to keep this domain if I have extra money to waste (.so domain cost $59 year, it isn't a small amount for a personal domain). Hopefully, I can keep it for my side projects.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="domain"></category></entry><entry><title>My OCA Java SE 7 Learning Journal</title><link href="http://yangsun.me/posts/2016-01/my-oca-java-se-7-learning-journal.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2016-02-06T18:48:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Yang Sun</name></author><id>tag:yangsun.me,2016-01-15:posts/2016-01/my-oca-java-se-7-learning-journal.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Since 2012, I started considering to take the OCA Java exam(It was Java 6 at that time). After three years, I am still in the nowhere. In December 2015, I finished reading Oracle's OCA/OCP Java SE 7 Programmer I &amp;amp; II Study Guide Part I and took the mock exam myself. I got 58% in score three times in a row and then, I decided not to take the exam until I can get 75% at least.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, nearly two months later, I am still where I am in December last year. I guess if I keep reading the book and practise with the sample questions, I might already get the certificate by now. What was I doing in my last two months? Ehmm... I can't remember.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ok, let's make it serious. From today - 15th January 2016, I will start reviewing it again. This time, I will keep writing some learning journal while I am reading the book and answering the sample question.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am using Google Doc for notes taking.
&lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/document/d/1IjwKHtsJoiTtNvqIbhtkyjJgPxiXISo_MYiiCGmlOIc/edit?usp=sharing"&gt;My Java SE 7 Programmer I Notes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let's see what I can get!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Update on 6th Feberary&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://yangsun.me/posts/2016-02/java-se-7-programmer-i-exam-passed.html"&gt;I passed my OCA Java SE 7 Programmer Exam!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="java"></category><category term="certificate"></category><category term="exam"></category></entry><entry><title>Hello World</title><link href="http://yangsun.me/posts/2016-01/hello-world.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2016-01-12T21:32:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Yang Sun</name></author><id>tag:yangsun.me,2016-01-12:posts/2016-01/hello-world.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Welcome to Yang Sun's blog&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hello World! This is my first post in this blog, I am going to use this blog as a place to write my thought on programming, reading and all the bits and bobs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As the time you see this post, the site is still under construction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Site under construction" src="http://yangsun.me/images/under_construction.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry></feed>