<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Yang Sun</title><link href="http://yangsun.me/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://yangsun.me/feeds/tech.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://yangsun.me/</id><updated>2016-02-04T12:45:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>My Domain Name is Back! - YangSun.me</title><link href="http://yangsun.me/posts/2016-02/my-domain-name-is-back-yangsun-me.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2016-02-04T12:45:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Yang Sun</name></author><id>tag:yangsun.me,2016-02-04:posts/2016-02/my-domain-name-is-back-yangsun-me.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I bought tons of domain in the last few years - qero.net, ebe.me, yang.so and the one I finally started using since yesterday afternoon - YangSun.me&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This domain was registered on an impulse in late 2014, but due to the workload from the study of my master course in UCD, it took me more than a year to get my hand on this domain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yesterday afternoon, I was reading a Java Cert book and started feeling boring with the tricky exam questions, so I did a quick lookup on my favourite domain reseller - &lt;a href="https://www.namecheap.com/?aff=96185"&gt;NameCheap&lt;/a&gt;. Yes! My expired domain can be registered now. I registered the domain and added three DNS settings, less than 12 hours, YangSun.me is up and running.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first time I notice &lt;a href="https://www.namecheap.com/?aff=96185"&gt;NameCheap&lt;/a&gt; is from GitHub. GitHub has a special perk for students called &lt;a href="https://education.github.com/pack"&gt;Student Developer Pack&lt;/a&gt;. The pack has many free bits for students(like free one year .me domain name from &lt;a href="https://www.namecheap.com/?aff=96185"&gt;NameCheap&lt;/a&gt;, free 50$ credit in &lt;a href="https://m.do.co/c/f68d634be5d8"&gt;DigitalOcean&lt;/a&gt;, and many more!)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This domain was first registered in December 2014 when I was attending my Master course in &lt;a href="http://www.ucd.ie"&gt;UCD&lt;/a&gt;. The main reason at that time was I want to create a website with my CV and my project on it. After I registered the domain for free with &lt;a href="https://www.namecheap.com/?aff=96185"&gt;NameCheap&lt;/a&gt;, I created an HTML page and link it to &lt;a href="http://github.com/s27y"&gt;my GitHub&lt;/a&gt;. Then I totally forgot about the website for a whole year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;What am I going do with this domain?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I always want to start writing to record the happiness, sadness and the random things happened in my life, but all I did was build a VPS/blog/WordPress and now pelican and then - totally forget about it after the website is up. This time, instead of building the website first, I am going to start writing first, then gradually improve the website.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;What about other domain names?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;ebe.me&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This domain was first registered five years ago when I was attending my undergraduate course in &lt;a href="www.dkit.ie"&gt;DKIT&lt;/a&gt;. Along with this domain, I also brought three years shared hosting plan from &lt;a href="www.goDadday.com"&gt;GoDaddy&lt;/a&gt;. At 2011, there was not much choice I can use to build a blog on a shared hosting plan, so I set up a WordPress on it, and I did wrote few blogs there in Chinese. Not long, it was abandoned.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;yang.so&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is my first attempt to create a personal brand - So Yang(So Young). I tried to write some Linux tips and hints on it, but then i gave up.
I am gooing to keep this domain if I have extra money to waste (.so domain cost $59 year, it isn't a small amount for a personal domain). Hopefully, I can keep it for my side projects.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="domain"></category></entry></feed>